<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My open source journey</title>
    <link>https://abdulhannanali.github.io/my-opensource-journey/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My open source journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Site Licensed under GNU GPL V3.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 14:33:19 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://abdulhannanali.github.io/my-opensource-journey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Linda Peng (Founder of Open Source Coding Community Codebuddies)</title>
      <link>https://abdulhannanali.github.io/my-opensource-journey/interview-with-linda-peng/content/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 14:33:19 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abdulhannanali.github.io/my-opensource-journey/interview-with-linda-peng/content/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This weekend I had the opportunity to interview &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lpnotes&#34;&gt;Linda Peng&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lpnotes&#34;&gt;Linda Peng&lt;/a&gt; is founder of an amazing open source community called &lt;a href=&#34;https://hangouts.codebuddies.org&#34;&gt;CodeBuddies&lt;/a&gt;. She founded &lt;a href=&#34;https://codebuddies.org&#34;&gt;CodeBuddies&lt;/a&gt; while she was learning to code herself, and is part of the community that helps with the journey of anyone learning to code, experts and beginners alike. I contacted her on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://codebuddiesmeet.slack.com&#34;&gt;Codebuddies Slack group&lt;/a&gt; and she was kind enough to answer my questions regarding the Codebuddies, open source and herself too. Thank you Linda! 😄. You can say hello to Linda on her twitter account &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lpnotes&#34;&gt;@lpnotes&lt;/a&gt;. Linda is a multi talented girl who codes, she is a great violinist too and you can check her videos playing violin on her YouTube &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCJvSYzVCH7IkaBlTh1zSYpw&#34;&gt;channel&lt;/a&gt;. They are awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can visit the CodeBuddies Github Repository &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lpatmo/cb&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are the interview questions I asked her and the answers she replied back with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tell-us-about-yourself-codebuddies-the-purpose-behind-it-and-it-s-beginnings:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Tell us about yourself, Codebuddies, the purpose behind it, and it&amp;rsquo;s beginnings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello, I’m Linda! I work as a front-end developer at &lt;a href=&#34;http://actionkit.com/&#34;&gt;actionkit.com&lt;/a&gt;. I’d never taken a computer science class, and I started CodeBuddies because I was frustrated by how hard it was to improve at coding by yourself &amp;ndash; even with all the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massive_open_online_course&#34;&gt;MOOCs&lt;/a&gt; and free resources out there &amp;ndash; if you did not have access to tech meetups or mentors close to where you lived. When I was first starting out, I personally benefited a lot from going to meetups and hackathons in NYC and learning from watching other people work. But then I discovered that scheduling a time with a study partner to walk through a coding tutorial together by screensharing via Google Hangouts was highly efficient, didn’t require a commute, and also helped me stay focused a lot better than if I was at a loud, social meetup. And thus the idea of peer-to-peer study motivation via virtual Google Hangouts was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CodeBuddies started out in the summer of 2014 as a bunch of Google group mailing lists, but has since expanded to include a Hangouts platform, a growing Slack community where an amazing group of volunteers consistently help each other out with code and advice and links to helpful resources, a Facebook group cross-run by The Odin Project volunteers, and a crowdsourced newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-you-started-the-project-was-it-just-between-you-and-your-peers-did-you-intend-to-grow-it-to-a-big-level-how-were-you-able-to-launch-it:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;When you started the project, was it just between you and your peers? Did you intend to grow it to a big level? How were you able to launch it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started the project in summer 2014, my goal was just to test out whether the idea of virtual hangouts could work as a learning enhancement. So I asked friends to study with me, or met strangers and pitched them the idea by linking them to a landing page about the idea and gave them access to a google group mailing list where they could propose their own study sessions/groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That summer, I had a lot of support from a creative community in NYC called &lt;a href=&#34;http://orbital.nyc&#34;&gt;Orbital&lt;/a&gt;, founded by the awesome &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/garychou&#34;&gt;Gary Chou&lt;/a&gt;, who had launched an &lt;a href=&#34;http://orbital.nyc/bootcamp/&#34;&gt;experimental bootcamp to help people launch their side projects&lt;/a&gt;. We met once a week for 12 weeks, and the experience forced me to launch things before I thought they were ready, and to continue iterating. If I hadn’t participated in the class and hadn’t had the support network of launching an idea with a group of peers, &lt;a href=&#34;http://codebuddies.org&#34;&gt;CodeBuddies&lt;/a&gt; would probably still be an idea stuck in my head. But because I was encouraged to test ideas early, I created the Google groups community &amp;ndash; which led to the creation of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://hangouts.codebuddies.org&#34;&gt;hangouts platform&lt;/a&gt;, and then to the creation of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://codebuddiesmeet.slack.com&#34;&gt;Slack community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a few ways, the side project bootcamp experience is what I want CodeBuddies to be: &lt;strong&gt;a community of people with their own goals, who motivate each other via consistent check-ins&lt;/strong&gt;. That’s a major reason I started the CodeBuddies anonymous crowdsourced newsletter &amp;ndash; it was a channel for people to share links to what they were working on, and hopefully be motivated to continue to work on it with the helpful presence of an audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My overall goal for the project, still, is to create spaces that help people connect and help each other be more productive / learn faster.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;since-it-s-a-big-open-source-project-now-how-do-you-solve-the-bugs-and-overall-manage-and-maintain-the-project-s-repo:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Since it&amp;rsquo;s a big open source project now. How do you solve the bugs and overall manage and maintain the project&amp;rsquo;s repo?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I track all the open features and bugs using Github issues, and label the specific issues that people could work on with the help wanted label.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;code-is-just-one-of-the-part-how-do-you-maintain-a-positive-community-of-people-around-this-open-source-project-who-are-willing-to-contribute-and-help-with-codebuddies:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Code is just one of the part, how do you maintain a positive community of people around this open source project who are willing to contribute and help with Codebuddies?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code learning community is incredible: people are incredibly kind to one another, generally, and are willing to pay it forward &amp;ndash; because at one point, they were stuck too, and it was a lot easier to get un-stuck with the help of a mentor. There’s also too much to learn, so not everyone has expertise on every single technical topic out there. I’ve seen mentees become mentors very quickly, and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My philosophy is just try to help as much as I can, in the name of paying it forward (because people definitely helped me when I was more clueless than I was now &amp;ndash; not that I’m not still clueless about a lot of things). And I think that positivity carries forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CodeBuddies also isn’t an organization in the traditional sense &amp;ndash; it doesn’t make any money, it’s not a non-profit or for-profit, it’s more or less all open-sourced and community-built, and I respect the time of the people who are willing to contribute.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-do-you-find-interesting-about-open-source-and-what-does-it-mean-to-you-how-has-open-source-changed-the-way-you-see-the-world:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;What do you find interesting about Open Source and what does it mean to you? How has open source changed the way you see the world?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet would be a lot different without open source. No open sourced libraries, no &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoproject.com/&#34;&gt;django&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubyonrails.org/&#34;&gt;Ruby on Rails&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meteor.com/&#34;&gt;Meteor&lt;/a&gt;. The tech industry is not boring because of open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making CodeBuddies open-sourced is probably the best thing I could have done for it. The project is better and more exciting because of the collective wisdom of all of its contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-can-people-participate-in-contributing-to-the-codebuddies:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;How can people participate in contributing to the codebuddies?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contribute by asking questions or helping out on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://codebuddiesmeet.herokuapp.com/&#34;&gt;CodeBuddies Slack channel&lt;/a&gt;, submitting a shout-out or link to a project to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://codebuddies.org/weekly/&#34;&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt;, testing out &lt;a href=&#34;http://codebuddies.org/todayilearned&#34;&gt;codebuddies.org/todayilearned&lt;/a&gt;, saying hello in the #codebuddies-meta channel on the Slack, or adding your name to indicate your interest in collaborating on Hangouts 2.0 &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/codebuddies-hangouts-platform-v2-googledoc&#34;&gt;bit.ly/codebuddies-hangouts-platform-v2-googledoc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;hangouts-2-0-is-under-development-what-do-you-want-it-to-accomplish-since-it-s-a-very-nice-example-of-the-evolution-of-a-community-oriented-open-source-project-can-you-tell-us-something-about-it:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Hangouts 2.0 is under development. What do you want it to accomplish? Since it’s a very nice example of the evolution of a community oriented open source project. Can you tell us something about it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mission of Hangouts 2.0 is to make it easier (than it currently is) for people to find silent study partners, pair programming partners, or project collaborators at any moment of the day. Right now Slack has been useful for chatting, but it’s still hard to tell who is working on what at any given moment, or might be working on the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-message-and-advice-do-you-want-to-give-to-pakistani-women-and-also-women-in-general-worldwide-who-want-to-come-in-the-stem-field-and-also-contribute-in-the-open-source-world-since-women-have-less-than-2-0-of-open-source-contributions:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;What message and advice do you want to give to Pakistani women and also women in general worldwide  who want to come in the STEM field  and also contribute in the open source world (since women have less than 2.0% of Open Source contributions)?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t understand all the reasons more Pakistani women aren’t in the STEM field, but I would encourage them to not be intimidated by STEM and to try it if they have the opportunity!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, knowing how to make code to improve the processes in your life &amp;ndash; or knowing how to make websites that has the potential to engage people around the world on the Internet &amp;ndash; is like a &lt;strong&gt;superpower&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key is to persevere!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;will-you-join-fossasia-summit-2016-from-march-18th-to-20th-in-singapore-it-s-the-largest-open-source-summit-of-asia-you-can-learn-more-here-http-2016-fossasia-org:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Will you join FOSSASIA summit 2016 from March 18th to 20th in Singapore? It’s the largest open source summit of Asia. You can learn more &lt;a href=&#34;http://2016.fossasia.org/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very cool! Not sure I can make it since I’m pretty far away, but sounds like a fun summit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you Linda! For such an awesome interview. Interview with Linda has been a really eye opening experience since Codebuddies is a fine example of how we can create a change and facilitate others in solving problems using the power of open source. I have taken the help of code buddies in the past and will continue to do so and also contribute to this amazing platform of ours. Please visit Codebuddies by clicking &lt;a href=&#34;http://hangouts.codebuddies.org&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s a picture of Linda with her violin!
&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/gw6XY2u.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Linda Peng with her violin: Picture courtesy of Linda Peng&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This interview was done as part of a Task in &lt;a href=&#34;https://codein.withgoogle.com&#34;&gt;Google CodeIn&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://fossasia.github.io&#34;&gt;FOSSASIA&lt;/a&gt; organization. FOSSASIA is playing a major role in supporting and promoting open source in Asian region. You can check out the FOSSASIA github organization &lt;a href=&#34;https://fossasia.github.io&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What open source means to me?</title>
      <link>https://abdulhannanali.github.io/my-opensource-journey/what-opensource-means-to-me/content/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 21:43:17 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abdulhannanali.github.io/my-opensource-journey/what-opensource-means-to-me/content/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-open-source-means-to-me:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;What open source means to me?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-source-in-general:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Open Source in general&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a topic that has really deep meaning for me cos open source means a lot of today&amp;rsquo;s world and today&amp;rsquo;s life would have been unimaginable without open source. For me open source is one of the evolutionary stages human beings are going through in order to make societies more collaborative, more helpful, and peaceful. It&amp;rsquo;s the open source spirit that&amp;rsquo;s about promoting creativity and freedom to use and create what ever we can think of in this awesome world. It&amp;rsquo;s about &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; having a monopoly of a few over human intellect but to use human intellect as a resource for the well being of the world we live in. So that cats can have a life they deserve. Open source can create harmony just as the Information sharing between our body parts make us a living being. It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Sharing&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;em&gt;SHARING IS CARING&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s about eliminating the culture of hostility and instead promoting harmony. 😄😄😄😄😄&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;open-source-in-tech:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Open Source in tech&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This I can actually talk about and make sense. OpenSource has been prevalent since the early days from Computers. It&amp;rsquo;s really important for innovation as a whole and that&amp;rsquo;s why it&amp;rsquo;s really important for Computer Science. From Homebrew hacker club to this day computer people. Even though we have come a long way from &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ENIAC&#34;&gt;ENIAC&lt;/a&gt; which was a product of accumulation of huge open source contributions over decades and couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been possible without the open source ideas around it&amp;rsquo;s founders, the basic principles even today are pretty much the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today the open source means the world for me as I daily work on open source technologies on my Laptop having Open Source Operating System called &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubuntu.org&#34;&gt;Kubuntu 15.10&lt;/a&gt;, in an Open Source text editor called &lt;a href=&#34;https://atom.io&#34;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt; on which I am currently typing this blog post, using Open Source run time environment called &lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org&#34;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt;. I use none of the frameworks which are not open source. Even a thought of closed source web development framework seems awful to me. I can go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; at any moment and open the source code of the development framework, I work on, called &lt;a href=&#34;https://expressjs.com&#34;&gt;ExpressJS&lt;/a&gt; and see for my self how all this works. What a relief, Humans are innately curious and the relief that no other party is stopping me from being curious is the best relief I can get in a day 😌😌😌😌😌. The sites out there I visit are also run hugely by open source software and that makes sense too cos I can learn what they use and can effectively contribute to the security and development of those sites too. (Inspired by this paragraph I have created a Gist including the open source projects. I use, in my daily routine. You can see it &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/abdulhannanali/b602082bb9a778ba1080&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This fact also helps that I have such an awesome community including awesome people who will be there to help me whenever I raise an issue and will welcome my contributions too. Even if they don&amp;rsquo;t accept my contributions they will tell me why they didn&amp;rsquo;t accept it so I can actually learn and improve and resubmit my contributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;open-source-for-education:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Open Source for education&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite introduced to the programming world before a major open source effort, it was due to the open source projects such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://edx.org&#34;&gt;edX&lt;/a&gt; by universities like &lt;a href=&#34;https://mit.edu&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://harvard.edu&#34;&gt;Harvard&lt;/a&gt; which introduced me to this programming world.
Open sourcing education has proven to have a really big impact, &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.mit.edu/2015/ahaan-rungta-mit-opencourseware-mitx-1116&#34;&gt;stories&lt;/a&gt; such as these are a proof of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;open-source-for-peace:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Open Source for Peace&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The really fun thing about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open-source_software&#34;&gt;OSS&lt;/a&gt; world online is that it&amp;rsquo;s the nicest place on internet too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People anywhere in the world can learn and grow together. This allows for mutual understanding and collaboration which is essential and can solve any issue no matter how big it is. Something governments aren&amp;rsquo;t really good at doing. This seems like a small thing but this can start such a powerful chain reaction and can ultimately be the cause of world peace. World peace is something I would really like to have. Can we all have some more world peace?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governments can also open source the software they have and this is one of the reasons I like and appreciate the projects such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://government.github.com&#34;&gt;government.github.com&lt;/a&gt;. If this is done effectively it&amp;rsquo;s a really cool thing because Governments can collaborate more effectively in improving their sectors. Really cool. Han?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also really inspired me to create an Open Source Project called &lt;a href=&#34;https://damp-ridge-2114.herokuapp.com&#34;&gt;thepeacepledge&lt;/a&gt;. Please sign up for this peace pledge. Your sign up matters. It&amp;rsquo;s open source and you can see the code and maybe learn something too &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/abdulhannanali/the-peace-pledge&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;purpose-of-writing-this:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Purpose of writing this&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a task assigned by &lt;a href=&#34;https://fossasia.github.io&#34;&gt;FOSSASIA&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://codein.withgoogle.com&#34;&gt;Google CodeIn 2015&lt;/a&gt;. FOSSASIA is a really awesome organization with purpose of improving the state of open source in the Asian continent which luckily carries most of the human weight. Please contribute to FOSSASIA since it&amp;rsquo;s really awesome, also share about FOSSASIA cos together we&amp;rsquo;ll make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;images-of-me-with-some-open-source-software-logos:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Images of me with some open source software logos :)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry! For bad quality. I will upload good pics too. I am quite beautiful in reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/RtIFe8r.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/gQNDRwJ.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/WrVedEj.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;FOSSASIA ACKNOWLEDGEMENT&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to setup a blog using Hugo</title>
      <link>https://abdulhannanali.github.io/my-opensource-journey/setup-hugo-blog/content/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 12:48:14 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abdulhannanali.github.io/my-opensource-journey/setup-hugo-blog/content/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugo-is-easiest-of-them-folks:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Hugo is easiest of them folks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey there! I&amp;rsquo;ve tried many of the static templating engines in the past. Most of them were based on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org&#34;&gt;node.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith&#34;&gt;Wintersmith&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://hexo.io&#34;&gt;Hexo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/flatiron/blacksmith&#34;&gt;BlackSmith&lt;/a&gt; but since I&amp;rsquo;ve tried Hugo I am not going back now. Hugo is the best Static Website Engine &lt;strong&gt;EVER&lt;/strong&gt;. Some of the features that are very impressive about Hugo include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s speed and performance (check out this impressive &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CdiDYZ51a2o&#34;&gt;Hugo Benchmark Video&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s ultra flexibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s awesome collaborative community&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within 9ms it renders the whole content for me again. I am literally like &lt;strong&gt;WOW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../wow.gif&#34; alt=&#34;WOW! HUGO IS AWESOME&#34; /&gt;
This was me after seeing the rendering time and speed of hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w7Ft2ymGmfc&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to see how you can create a functional site with &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; under 2 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-s-get-started-with-hugo:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s get started with Hugo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enough of the talk. Let&amp;rsquo;s get to the real thing here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;downloading-and-installing-hugo:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Downloading and Installing Hugo&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing hugo is relatively easy and you have to deal with less &lt;strong&gt;CLI&lt;/strong&gt; sometimes when intalling Hugo. It&amp;rsquo;s also really cool to install it too. You can go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugo/releases&#34;&gt;Hugo Release Page&lt;/a&gt; and download the binary for your computer depending on your Operating System version. You can also compile the source code yourself but we won&amp;rsquo;t go into that &lt;em&gt;Nittttty Grittty&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: At the time of the writing this the current Hugo release is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugo/releases/tag/v0.15&#34;&gt;v0.15&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The installation process, as you know, varies depending upon the operating system but it&amp;rsquo;s relatively simple. For me it was just a couple of clicks and I am using &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubuntu.org/&#34;&gt;KUbuntu 15.10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;setting-up-a-new-blog:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Setting up a new blog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been simpler than what Hugo has made it for us. Let&amp;rsquo;s setup a blog called &lt;strong&gt;My desi journeys&lt;/strong&gt;. Here we&amp;rsquo;ll post our desi journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can play with Hugo yourself and explore all the options Hugo provide by typing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;hugo help
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or better you can go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/overview/introduction/&#34;&gt;Hugo Docs&lt;/a&gt; for details and instructions on pretty much everything about Hugo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to start with our desi journeys we&amp;rsquo;ll type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;hugo new site &amp;quot;my-desi-journey&amp;quot;
cd my-desi-journey
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this will generate the bare bones of our hugo static site in a directory &lt;code&gt;my-desi-journey&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; will change our &lt;code&gt;working directory&lt;/code&gt; to this blog. Now let&amp;rsquo;s create a new post. This is also relatively very simple&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;hugo new welcome/content.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a &lt;code&gt;welcome&lt;/code&gt; folder will be generated in the &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt; folder. This folder is what hugo calls section and contains our &lt;code&gt;markdown&lt;/code&gt; files. To read more about them go &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/content/sections/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not familiar already with Markdown you should be. It&amp;rsquo;s the thing these days but the great thing is it&amp;rsquo;s also very simple. Click &lt;a href=&#34;http://git.io/vCMcp&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to read more about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will notice something like this on top of &lt;code&gt;content.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34;&gt;+++
date = &amp;quot;2016-01-01T12:39:20+05:00&amp;quot;
draft = true
title = &amp;quot;Welcome&amp;quot;
+++
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not very markdown style in my honest opinion. This is called Front Matter in this case it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/toml-lang/toml&#34;&gt;TOML&lt;/a&gt;. Front matter will contain your post meta data such as title, date etc. Read more about Front Matter &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/content/front-matter/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Down below the front matter you can add standard markdown finally. For this blog post I am adding this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-md&#34;&gt;# Welcome to a blog about my desi journeys

This is where we discuss all that desi cool + odd stuff.
OH YES! THIS IS THE SITE!!!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after adding the markdown let&amp;rsquo;s run the very first static version of site. Luckily for editing purposes hugo offers a really reliable and &lt;strong&gt;EXTREMELY FAST&lt;/strong&gt; server which also watches for changes as you make them. Pretty cool? Yeah I know 😉😂😉.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s run it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;hugo server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now go to to the link it specifies for the running web server and you will see a nice clean blank HTML page. That&amp;rsquo;s all good but where&amp;rsquo;s the content. This is where Hugo themes come in the equation. They teach Mr. Hugo some rendering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-a-nice-cool-hugo-theme:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Getting a nice cool Hugo theme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The awesome community of Hugo has made some really cool themes for Hugo. You can go and check&amp;rsquo;em out here at &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io&#34;&gt;themes.gohugo.io&lt;/a&gt; and select the one you really love ❤️ ❤️ ❤️ .
I am using &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/allegiant/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ALLEGIANT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the same one as this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s  execute some commands to use this theme&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;mkdir themes
cd themes
git clone https://github.com/brycematheson/allegiant.git
cd ..
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first command will create a themes directory. We then change our &lt;code&gt;working directory&lt;/code&gt; to this directory.
After that third command will clone the &lt;code&gt;allegiant&lt;/code&gt; themes repository in the local themes folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Executing this will use the allegiant theme and build the drafts too&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;hugo --theme=allegiant --buildDrafts server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now if we go on to our web server. We can see our beautiful site with some content too.
That&amp;rsquo;s pretty nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;configuring-our-hugo-blog:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Configuring our hugo blog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some changes you still have to make to the blog hugo generated for you. You have to especially change the configurations. Modifying the &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; will do it. The &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; contains values for different variables our hugo blog uses for generating the static content.
I have modified &lt;code&gt;my-desi-journey&lt;/code&gt; configuration file to look like this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34;&gt;baseurl = &amp;quot;https://abdulhannanali.github.io/my-desi-journey&amp;quot;
languageCode = &amp;quot;en-us&amp;quot;
title = &amp;quot;My open source journey&amp;quot;
author = &amp;quot;Hannan Ali&amp;quot;
copyright = &amp;quot;Site Licensed under GNU GPL V3.0&amp;quot;
canonifyurls = true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also specify the theme in the configuratin file by adding the line below&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34;&gt;theme = &amp;quot;allegiant&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will save you the hassle of specifying the same theme in the command line each time you run your Hugo Server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the configurations which are necessary in most cases. &lt;code&gt;allegiant&lt;/code&gt; also has it&amp;rsquo;s own configurations variables which you can set too. Read about configuring allegiant &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/allegiant#configuration&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To read more about configurations and what else can you do with them click &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/overview/configuration/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;generating-static-content-for-uploading:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Generating static content for uploading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now there&amp;rsquo;s just one step left, generate the static content to upload to our site. This is done by omitting &lt;code&gt;server&lt;/code&gt; keyword from the command we used above&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;hugo --theme=allegiant --buildDrafts
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will have a &lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt; folder generated in your hugo blog root directory. The contents of this &lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt; folder are what we need to upload to the static server in order to display it&amp;rsquo;s contents. We are done here YAYYY! You have your very own cooked desi blog. Congrats!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../woo.gif&#34; alt=&#34;WOOO!&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;source-code-and-hugo-docs:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Source code and Hugo Docs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have made the source code of my-desi-journey available on Github if you want to take a look. Here is the repo &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/abdulhannanali/my-desi-journey&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;. Also don&amp;rsquo;t forget to check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hugo.io&#34;&gt;hugo docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/hugo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hugo Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy new year</title>
      <link>https://abdulhannanali.github.io/my-opensource-journey/happynewyear/content/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 12:44:03 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abdulhannanali.github.io/my-opensource-journey/happynewyear/content/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;happy-new-year-2016:05301946b75cb988bc2be8549079b4fa&#34;&gt;Happy new year 2016.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../hny.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Happy New Year Google&#34; /&gt;
Hope best for you in this awesome year and yeah this is that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/doodles&#34;&gt;Google Happy New Year Image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://abdulhannanali.github.io/my-opensource-journey/helloworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 12:39:20 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abdulhannanali.github.io/my-opensource-journey/helloworld/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The compulsory hello world post :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>