<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open on My open source journey</title>
    <link>https://abdulhannanali.github.io/my-opensource-journey/tags/open/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open on My open source journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Site Licensed under GNU GPL V3.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 02:57:38 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://abdulhannanali.github.io/my-opensource-journey/tags/open/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture of information sharing</title>
      <link>https://abdulhannanali.github.io/my-opensource-journey/culture-of-open-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 02:57:38 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abdulhannanali.github.io/my-opensource-journey/culture-of-open-information/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;All the living organisms on this planet including humans are consuming the information from their surroundings somehow and making choices suitable for their sustainable development and long life. Open and wide spread and reach of &lt;strong&gt;information&lt;/strong&gt; is really important for any society and individual to develop. Making sense of some of infinite supply of information and doing something with it is what makes us Humans. It&amp;rsquo;s very much like food, what we eat has direct impact on our body. It&amp;rsquo;s sometimes so important that KFC won&amp;rsquo;t let you get into their kitchen or CocaCola into their factory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information is the best thing too cos it just doesn&amp;rsquo;t reduce if we share it with others rather, we can create something beautiful out of combining various sources of information. But, I still don&amp;rsquo;t know why in some regions of the world people are still reluctant to share the information they have. This is all going to change very soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;narrow-minded-attitude-towards-information:d680e8a854a7cbad6d490c445cba2eba&#34;&gt;Narrow minded attitude towards information&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see clouds between the people and even the information that&amp;rsquo;s mostly beneficial for us. There certainly exists a really deep selfishness in the behaviors of the people and the way they deal with the information. I&amp;rsquo;ve found it to be crazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people want to block the sources they use for information for others or at best to keep secret what useful stuff they already know. Limiting information sources for others leads to limiting our own resources and our creativity as a society too. This narrow mindedness can be experienced all over the world in various forms at any level, from billionaire human rights violator feudal lords not letting schools build to some street mullah not letting girls to educate because of his foolish narrow mindedness. This has definitely lead to a poor global image of the country I live in &lt;strong&gt;Pakistan&lt;/strong&gt; and let&amp;rsquo;s acknowledge, it&amp;rsquo;s a reality, everything is quite screwed because of the mistakes we make daily and we don&amp;rsquo;t even know that we are making mistakes which can harm us a lot in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blockade of information leads to less opportunities for people to thrive and in turn is the cause of every worst possible crime humanity has ever commited in this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The information gap between different circle in same places is wide and definitely harms the situtation. A classical example is of the different education systems in same city. Reaching from really good education systems to systems which are really good at  teaching nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How come we can be so touchy about information, when it too was provided to the world by some human seven seas far. It&amp;rsquo;s just &lt;strong&gt;plainly&lt;/strong&gt; wrong. Information has no owner. If anyone thinks like thi, it&amp;rsquo;s very limiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only if they understand, sharing information is a path to greatness not stopping it from spreading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;internet-and-it-s-positive-effects-on-me:d680e8a854a7cbad6d490c445cba2eba&#34;&gt;Internet and it&amp;rsquo;s positive effects on me&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve certainly been curious to some extent all my life but I was lucky enough to get access to world&amp;rsquo;s largest source of information &lt;strong&gt;The Internet&lt;/strong&gt; and that has really helped me in knowing about the different cultures, different beliefs and non beliefs and all kinds of people all over the world. Studying in a school where teachers still use sticks on children, Islamic Studies teacher still advocate for extremist and anti American point of views and total standard of education is based on rote learning. Internet aka Open World of Inforamtion was The One Thing that helped to make my perspectives a little more wider. It has helped me quite enough in answering important questions I needed answers for. Better yet, I didn&amp;rsquo;t look forward to some ignorant &lt;strong&gt;Mullah&lt;/strong&gt; for these answers. Otherwise, it was going to be a really bad situation for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through Internet I was able to access the wide ocean of awesome information and study from the materials provided by the world&amp;rsquo;s best universities such as Harvard and MIT. I was able to know about a wider global perspective and respect others opinions and acknowledge where my country is doing wrong. Write some computer programs too, which I definitely love to do. Do some research and best of all enjoy the sense of freedom to learn anything and connect freely. A &lt;strong&gt;basic human right&lt;/strong&gt; in the world, I believe. Internet is really powerful and I believe I haven&amp;rsquo;t used it to it&amp;rsquo;s full power yet but journey is going to be different for everyone though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t achieved anything worthy till now, but I am happy because I have that liberating feels in me. That, I have the opportunity and the resource for what ever I wanna achieve. I need this to be possible for more and more people in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;bringing-a-change-in-our-ways:d680e8a854a7cbad6d490c445cba2eba&#34;&gt;Bringing a change in our ways&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the best time to live in this world because no one can now actually stop you from what you really want to know. Information is going to spread to everyone and lots of it. Information is not going to become anyone&amp;rsquo;s entity anymore. Narrow minded authorities might resist it for sometime but for how long? Not much!!! People who want others to stay in darkness might resist it too but not for too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current education system is neither equal and nor scalable to fulfill this world&amp;rsquo;s educational needs and that&amp;rsquo;s why internet is going to be necessary in the future. This is why it&amp;rsquo;s really important for us to be open minded, accepting of the other cultures and having an open and sharing attitude towards information instead of our same old approach. Also, it&amp;rsquo;s one of the reasons I really believe in organizations like &lt;a href=&#34;http://khanacademy.org/&#34;&gt;KhanAcademy&lt;/a&gt; becaues it&amp;rsquo;s definitely going to be the way in which students will get educated in the future (for more information read Sal Khan&amp;rsquo;s Book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15898640-the-one-world-schoolhouse&#34;&gt;The One World Schoolhouse: Education Reimagined&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;open-information-for-girls:d680e8a854a7cbad6d490c445cba2eba&#34;&gt;Open information for girls&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There still exists countless villages in Pakistan where this narrow way of thinking is the cause of no school for girls yet. NO SCHOOL! I have a firm belief that if we create some harmony in how we share information among the 7 billion people in the world, we can solve some pretty big global issues. I desire an open and peaceful world for everyone and this is a way to go. Let&amp;rsquo;s build this open world using tools like internet so finally we can streamline our workflow and think beyond our planet too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of so many intelligent girls just like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malala_Yousafzai&#34;&gt;Malala Yousafzai&lt;/a&gt; who are unable to contribute to the development of this world, because of some idiotic and limiting thought. We are missing so many great women leaders in this world. Pakistan has the lowest number of women in workforce today. All this is because of the closed and BS approach Pakistani people has to the actual and open information. If provided better opportunities for information, there are awesome organizations like &lt;a href=&#34;http://leanin.org/&#34;&gt;Lean In&lt;/a&gt; which can definitely help women in Leaning In. Many of the girls in Pakistan aren&amp;rsquo;t enjoying the same optimism and interesting career choices because they just don&amp;rsquo;t know, how much they can achieve in this world and be like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sheryl_Sayndberg&#34;&gt;Sheryl Sandberg&lt;/a&gt;. We certainly need more women in leadership as well as STEM in this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;bringing-a-change:d680e8a854a7cbad6d490c445cba2eba&#34;&gt;Bringing a change&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just a big disgrace, because the biggest factor that&amp;rsquo;s coming in way is definitely the culture and our ownselves. It&amp;rsquo;s the way we view and think about this problem and this should change immediately. No more wait for the solution to this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not the world any more in which we can achieve something with the help of arms. But, what can help us is the open and equal access for information for every peaceful body. It&amp;rsquo;s the world of using these just amazing and mind blowing resources to create innovative solutions for the problems we face daily in our lives, to make our lives even better and play a role in the evolution of humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, there are occuring shameful acts of violence, terror and ignorance in Pakistan because of the narrow minds of humans here. We can only change it, if we think ahead of our personal interests and think of the ways to improve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems odd that I am even advocating for this in 21st century. This problem should have been already solved. But as it still exists because of the negligence towards it by our ancestors, let&amp;rsquo;s just get together and put our resources to use in improving the situation here and all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to do everything possible in order to make possible the access to open information and develop a culture of sharing. This is demanded from Pakistan by the world and the other countries too where all people aren&amp;rsquo;t provided open access to the information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DISCLAIMER: THIS IS AN OPINIONATED ARTICLE AND THESE ARE MY PERSONAL THOUGHTS. YOU ARE IN NO WAY BOUND TO ACCEPT THESE AND I AM IN NO WAY RESPONSIBLE IF YOU BROKE DOWN AFTER READING THIS ARTICLE 🍷🍷🍷🍷🍷&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;thank-you-to-my-mom:d680e8a854a7cbad6d490c445cba2eba&#34;&gt;Thank you to my mom&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This free and open access of information I have got is because of my mom. She is the best mom in the world and a true inspiration for me. She pays for the internet too. So Yeah!!! 💗💗💗💗💗💓💓💓💓💕💕💕💕&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&#34;may-the-force-be-with-you-all:d680e8a854a7cbad6d490c445cba2eba&#34;&gt;May the force be with you all! 😄&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>